<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Malice and injustice exist by design on jimihol&#39;s website</title>
    <link>https://jimishol.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Malice and injustice exist by design on jimihol&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 16:09:06 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jimishol.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meet circle of fifths on music, through an analog clock</title>
      <link>https://jimishol.github.io/post/circle_of_fifths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 16:09:06 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimishol.github.io/post/circle_of_fifths/</guid>
      <description>In my youth I studied classical guitar. I read a lot of sheet music and knew how to use key signatures. But I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to identify, at a glance, the major or minor scale pair that defines a, non-trivial, signature. I thought this ability belonged only to very experienced musicians. A few days ago, I realized that I was completely wrong. Identifying the pair of scales that defines a key signature is as easy as using a wristwatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My introduction to game theory</title>
      <link>https://jimishol.github.io/post/game_theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 15:19:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimishol.github.io/post/game_theory/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading the book &amp;ldquo;An introduction to Game Theory&amp;rdquo; by Martin J. Osborne. A truly wonderful book, which seems to have influenced even my everyday thinking. Its only problem, for me, is that it tries too hard not to make it necessary, for its reader, to use even elementary algebra.
Its beauty, however, lies mainly in the carefully chosen exercises. At the beginning of the book, they seem so elementary that they make you wonder, and even bore you to solve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As a Book for bridge card game</title>
      <link>https://jimishol.github.io/post/like-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 22:56:34 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimishol.github.io/post/like-book/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Once in a blue moon an idea sweeps through the bridge world and revolutionises thinking. The so-called Law of Total Tricks is so accurate in assessing potential in the contested auction and so easy to use (meaning in the book) that it is being introduced early and used to justify many subsequent bidding decisions.&amp;rdquo;
From the book &amp;ldquo;Understanding the contested auction&amp;rdquo; of Ron Klinger and Andrew Kambites.
Once upon a time, I was playing bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dark Ananke theme</title>
      <link>https://jimishol.github.io/post/dark_theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:28:57 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimishol.github.io/post/dark_theme/</guid>
      <description>All necessary files are copied from ananke/layout folder to corresponding project&amp;rsquo;s/layout folder and modified there. So, in order to have a dark theme, copy the below files. (Delete extention .txt, if you directly copy them.) You do not have to modify them.
project&amp;rsquo;s/layout/index.html. project&amp;rsquo;s/layout/_default/list.html. project&amp;rsquo;s/layout/_default/summary-with-image.html. project&amp;rsquo;s/layout/_default/summary.html. project&amp;rsquo;s/layout/_default/taxonomy.html. project&amp;rsquo;s/layout/post/list.html. project&amp;rsquo;s/layout/post/summary.html. Last, make sure your config.toml has the following color parameters you like
[params] text_color = &amp;#34;white&amp;#34; background_color_class = &amp;#34;bg-black&amp;#34; body_classes = &amp;#34;avenir bg-black&amp;#34; aux_text_color = &amp;#34;silver&amp;#34; bg_button_color = &amp;#34;bg-black&amp;#34; bg_button_hover_color = &amp;#34;hover-bg-dark-gray&amp;#34; I picked color names from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stockfish Chess Engine Server</title>
      <link>https://jimishol.github.io/post/stockfish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 21:12:52 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimishol.github.io/post/stockfish/</guid>
      <description>For linux users it seems pretty easy and natural to let scid chess databases, on low CPU and RAM devices, to use stockfish chess engine that runs on a more powerful server.
We start by installing stockfish onto our most powerful machine.
In my case a desktop with 32G RAM and 8 CPU cores with 2 threads per core, that means 16 threads.
Stockfish server The chess engine will run only when the user is logged in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video game Pioneer analysis</title>
      <link>https://jimishol.github.io/post/pioneer_economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimishol.github.io/post/pioneer_economy/</guid>
      <description>Years ago, got nostalgic for the time of youth and searched an old video game Elite I played on ZX Spectrum. Got upon pioneer. I loved it and tried to help in order for players to have stronger feeling of progress. I did a lengthy analysis in a relevant repository. The main idea was finally accepted, but the consequence to control the progress of player was still to come. I do not play the game any more but one great feature it has, is that supports mod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The polyhedron with the minimum of vertices, which considers itself a doughnut</title>
      <link>https://jimishol.github.io/post/pyramid-torus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimishol.github.io/post/pyramid-torus/</guid>
      <description>Paper cut unfold of a Császár polyhedron It is called Császár polyhedron
(Its dual is the Szilassi polyhedron).
Tutorial I was never able to construct Szilassi by myself, but there it follows how i constructed Császár polyhedron.
Algebraic start The Euler characteristic X of a torus is zero.
So our torus has V-E+F=0, where V=vertices, E=edges and F=faces.
We can assume all faces are triangles. So, E=3F/2 (cause with 3F we count each edge twice).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jimishol.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimishol.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Earth Observation NASA (Date Created:2010-08-23) As my mother language is Greek, my publications are sometimes written in Greek and sometimes in English, depending on who they are addressed to. (I have no intention of translating them).
Linux I am an enthusiastic user of Linux systems and have been using them exclusively in all areas for almost two decades. Mathematics Mathematics and rational thinking have always been the mainstays and shaped my everyday thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autobiograpy</title>
      <link>https://jimishol.github.io/autobiograpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jimishol.github.io/autobiograpy/</guid>
      <description>I am Greek and live in Greece. Thirty years ago it was taken for granted, under normal circumstances, that I would be alive after thirty years. Today, the exact opposite is true.
My skills and knowledge should be irrelevant as evidence of the truth of what I post. I have never liked the logical fallacy of authority. As readers, you yourself are responsible for what you consider right and wrong. So, instead of biography, let me paraphrase the GNU GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
